Guide to the University of Utah Audio-Visual Archive collection compilation videos 2005/2012
Multimedia Archives, J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah
University of Utah Audio-Visual Archive collection compilation videos
2005-2012
University of Utah Libraries, Special Collections Audio Visual Archives Special Collections 295 South 1500 East Salt Lake City, Utah 84112-0860 801-581-8864 http://www.lib.utah.edu/collections/multimedia-archives/
A0100
University of Utah Audio-Visual Archive
28 DVDs, 4 VHS videocassettes, and 3 Mini-DV videocassettes
The University of Utah Audio-Visual Archive collection compilation videos (2005-2012) consist of videos produced by the Audio-Visual Archive for promotions, tours and exhibits in the Special Collections reading room, other venues, and online. These videos were edited together by J. Willard Marriott Library staff using footage from other existing audio-visual collections. The University of Utah Audio-Visual Archive is a part of the Multimedia division of Special Collections at the J. Willard Marriott Library.
Historical Note
The Multimedia Archives contain the non-textual archives of the Special Collections Department of the J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah. The holdings are divided into two sections: the Photographs and the Audio-Visual materials. The Photograph Archive houses over 1300 separate photograph collections, which together contain approximately 1.7 million photographs representing almost all historic formats such as daguerreotypes, tintypes, cartes-de-viste, ambrotypes, albumen prints, panoramas, and cyanotypes, as well as more modern color and black and white prints, transparencies, and negatives. The Audio-Visual Archive contains over 900 collections and includes; audio cassettes, reel-to-reel tapes, vinyl recording discs, VHS, 8mm, Super-8, 16mm, and 35mm film and more.
The University of Utah Audio-Visual Archive collection compilation videos (2005-2012) consist of videos produced by the Audio-Visual Archive for promotions, tours and exhibits in the Special Collections reading room, other venues, and online. These videos were edited together by J. Willard Marriott Library staff using footage from other existing audio-visual collections and are available to view on DVD. All of
Materials are arranged either by subject matter or chronologically by compilation date, depending on date of accession.
Materials must be used on-site; no use of original material, access copies will be made available for viewing. Five business days advanced notice required. Access to parts of this collection may be restricted under provisions of state or federal law, condition of the material, or by donor.
See also the Multimedia Archives productions audio-visual collection (A0704), a collection of audio and video works by outside artists featuring materilas from the Audio-Visual and Photograph Archives.
Utah; Montage; Exhibit; Colleges and Universities; Moving Images; Moving images
- Audio-Visual Archive clip show, 2009; DVD (Disc 1-3)
  Montage of video highlights from Audio-Visual Archive collections (edited by Jonatahan Hepworth). Collections featured:
  A0002 University of Utah basketball
  A0012 Avard Fairbanks
  A0276 Burton W. Musser
  A0303 KUTV news
  A0319 University of Utah football
  A0354 Al Brain
  A0389 Wallace Stegner
  A0391 Alf Engen
  A0422 J. Willard Marriott Library
  A0431 KUED
  A0511 Charles Eggert
  A0832 Trent Harris (including Mike Cassidy)
  A0935 Joseph Peery
  A0938 O.L. "Brig" Tapp
  A0942 Jack Currey
  A0972 Jerry Andersch
  A0981 Looking for a Space (see also A0831 Judith Dwan Hallet)
- Audio-Visual Archive clip show, A0303 KUTV U-matic clip show, 2009; 2010; DVD (Disc 4-5)
  This disc contains complete and shortened versions of the Audio-Visual Archive clip show (edited by Jonathan Hepworth) as well as a montage of clips taken from the U-matic videocassettes in the KUTV news collection (A0303) (edited by Molly Rose Creel). The KUTV U-matic clip show was designed to demonstrate the value of the material recorded on this format and call attention to the need for its preservation.
- Ski Archives montage, 2011; DVD (Disc 6-8)
  Video highlights from collections related to the history of skiing in the Intermountain West (edited by Molly Rose Creel). Collections featured:
  A0544 Utah Travel Council
  A0622 Suzy Harris Rytting
  A0674 International Sports Broadcasting
  A0895 Robert C. Ecker
  A0974 United States Ski and Snowboard Association (USSA)
  A1056 Snowbird Ski and Summer Resort
- Utah parade clip show, 2010; DVD (Disc 9-11)
  Footage of historic Utah parades celebrating various holidays and local events throughout the 20th century (edited by Molly Rose Creel). Collections featured:
  A0286 Japanese American Citizens League (JACL)
- A0303 KUTV Speed Week montage, 2009; DVD (Disc 12-13)
  Video highlights from news reports on Speed Week at Utah's Bonneville Salt Flats 1970s-1980s (edited by Molly Rose Creel).
- A0303 KUTV new year's resolution montage, 2009; DVD (Disc 14-15)
  Video highlights from news reports on new year's resolutions by Utah citizens and politicians (edited by Molly Rose Creel).
- A0303 KUTV Speed Week montage, new year's resolution montage, 2009; DVD (Disc 16)
- A0162 James Fletcher space travel montage, 2011; DVD (Disc 17-18)
  Video highlights of space travel footage from the collection of James Fletcher, former University of Utah president and National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) administrator (edited by Molly Rose Creel). Much of this footage comes from official NASA videos released during Fletcher's tenure there.
- Keene Curtis tribute videos, undated; DVD (Disc 19-20)
  Video tributes to Utah born actor Keene Curtis (1923-2002) (edited by Justin Riley).
- Veterans Day military footage loop, 2011; DVD (Disc 21)
  Montage of military footage created to celebrate the anniversary of Veterans' Day on November 11, 2011: 11/11/11 (edited by Molly Rose Creel). Collections featured:
  A0029 Lester H. Fronk
  A0094 Charles R. and Jane A. Thompsen
  A1054 U.S.S. Salt Lake City
- A0694 SLOC promo loop, 2012; DVD (Disc 22)
  A collection of advertisements and promotional videos for the 2002 Winter Olympic Games in Salt Lake City, Utah. These videos were produced by the Salt Lake Organizing Committe (SLOC) and compiled here to celebrate the 10th anniversary of the 2002 Olympics.
- A0797 Spy Hop Olympic loop: "Messages: A 2002 Winter Olympics Documentary", 2012; DVD (Disc 23)
  This documentary about visitors' perceptions of Salt Lake City during the 2002 Winter Olympic Games was produced by teens at Spy Hop Productions. This disc contains the loop version of the video on display in the Special Collections reading room during the celebrtion of the 10th anniversary of the 2002 Olympics.
- A0946 Mickey Ibarra tribute video, 2012; DVD (Disc 24)
  Highlights from the audio-visual (A0946) and photograph (P1513) collections of Mickey Ibarra, a Utah native and advisor to President William Jefferson Clinton (edited by Molly Rose Creel). This video features the complete audio of Ibarra's speech at the 2000 dedication of the Millennium Bridge at Soboba in San Jacinto, California.
- University of Utah football loop, 2012; DVD (Disc 25)
  Highlights from University of Utah football games and spirit events 1940s-1990s (researched by John Hammer, edited by Ben Sandberg). Most footage in this silent video comes from the University of Utah football coach's films (A0319). Other featured collections include University of Utah Alumni Association (A0235) and KUTV news (A0303).
- Tuesday noon timecode, 2005 January 18; DVD (Disc 26)
  Highlights from the Utah Independent Film Archive compiled for public screening by Jimi Jones. Many of these films were produced at the University of Utah or by University of Utah faculty and alumni. Part I (55:39):
  "Nurture" (A0047 Kevin Don Hanson)
  "Relay"
  "Spring City" (A0825 Sue Jensen Weeks)
  "Subway" (A0832 Trent Harris)
  "The Cufflink" (A0809 Stephen Williams)
  "All Night Coffee Shop" (A0807 Mario DeAngelis)
  This compilation also exists on MiniDV (26a) and VHS (26b)
- Tuesday night timecode, 2005 January 18; DVD (Disc 27)
  Highlights from the Utah Independent Film Archive compiled for public screening by Jimi Jones. Many of these films were produced at the University of Utah or by University of Utah faculty and alumni. Part II (1:24:07):
  "For My Father" (A0809 Stephen Williams)
  Unidentified experimental short
  Unidentified stop motion animated short
  "Not an Ordinary Classic"
  "Tourist" (A0825 Sue Jensen Weeks)
  "Vernal" (A0832 Trent Harris)
  Unidentified experimental short (A0755 Jimi Jones)
  "Creative Passings" (A0762 Elizabeth and Jimmy Miklavcic)
  "The Projectionist: A Love Story" (A0807 Mario DeAngelis)
  "Broken" (A0811 Robbin Shahani)
  "Grass, Bolex, Plus-X, Guitar" (A0806 David Baddley)
  "Walking in the Valley of the Gods" (A0773 Steven Pecchia-Bekkum)
  This compilation also exists on MiniDV (27a) and VHS (27b, 27c)
- Wednesday noon timecode, 2005 January 19; DVD (Disc 28)
  Highlights from the Utah Independent Film Archive compiled for public screening by Jimi Jones. Many of these films were produced at the University of Utah or by University of Utah faculty and alumni. Part III (58:48):
  "The Giant Brine Shrimp" (A0832 Trent Harris, directed by Mike Cassidy)
  "A Chapter of Quiet Fire" (A0770 Masashi Kamimura)
  "Move It" (A0831 Judity Dwan Hallet, A0673 Ririe-Woodbury Dance Company)
  "The Perfect Babysitter" (A0811 Robbin Shahani)
  "The Amalgam Base 10 Digital/Analogue Audio History Study in 4 Languages
  This compilation also exists on MiniDV (28a) and VHS (28b)